macmillandictionary.com 2019-08-29

# Privacy policy for Macmillan Dictionary: the Free Online English Dictionary and Thesaurus

This is the privacy policy ("policy") for the website [https://www.macmillandictionary.com](https://www.macmillandictionary.com/) which is run and provided by Springer Nature Limited, 4 Crinan Street, London, N1 9XW, United Kingdom ( **we** , **us** and **our** ).

We will only use the personal data gathered over this website as set out in this policy. Below you will find information on how we use your personal data, for which purposes your personal data is used, with whom it is shared and what control and information rights you may have.

## I. Summary of our processing activities

The following summary provides you with a quick overview of the processing activities that are undertaken on our website. You will find more detailed information under the indicated sections below.

  * When you visit our website for informational reasons without setting up an account, only limited personal data will be processed to provide you with the website itself (see section III).
  * In case you register for one of our services (e.g. discussion forum), further personal data will be processed in the scope of such services (see section IV).
  * Furthermore, your personal data will be used to provide you with interesting advertising for our services and products (see section VII) and for statistical analysis that helps us to improve our website (see section VIII). Additionally, we improve your website experience with third party content (see section IX).
  * Your personal data may be disclosed to third parties (see section X) that might be located outside your country of residence; potentially, different data protection standards may apply (see section XI).
  * We have implemented appropriate safeguards to secure your personal data (see section XII) and retain your personal data only as long as necessary (see section XIII).
  * Under the legislation applicable to you, you may be entitled to exercise certain rights with regard to the processing of your personal data (see section XIV).

## II. Definitions

  * **Personal data** : means any information relating to a natural person who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, or an online identifier.
  * **Processing** : means any operation which is performed on personal data, such as collection, recording, organisation, structuring, storage, adaptation or any kind of disclosure or other use.

## III. Informational use of the website

When you visit our website for informational reasons, i.e. without registering for any of our provided services and without providing us with personal data in any other form, we may automatically collect additional information about you which will contain personal data only in limited cases and which is automatically recognized by our server, such as:

  * the website from which you have been directed to our offer
  * the date and time of your requests
  * your device type, screen resolution and browser version
  * your internet service provider
  * information on your operating system, including language settings
  * information on the offers you have visited on our website
  * IP address

We use such information only to assist us in providing an effective service (e.g. to adapt our website to the needs of your device or to allow you to log in to our website), and to collect broad demographic information for anonymised, aggregated use.

The personal data automatically collected is necessary for us to provide the website, Article 6 sec. 1 sent. 1 lit. b GDPR, and for our legitimate interest to guarantee the website's stability and security, Article 6 sec. 1 sent. 1 lit. f GDPR.

Personal data that is collected automatically is anonymized immediately OR is retained for 1 month and properly erased afterwards.

## IV. Information about the specific uses that require registration

For the use of the following services you will be required to set up an account. We may collect some personal data like your name or alias name or social media login details. You can request to get your personal data deleted if you wish to. This processing is based on Article 6 sec. 1 sent. 1 lit. b.

## 1\. Use of our discussion forum

We use a third party application for our Discussion forum, which helps collect/share comments from visitors. This forum can be accessed and read without registration. Anything you post on the discussion forum will be available to a broader public; you can delete your posts at any point in time. In this discussion forum you are not obliged to provide your real name but can use an alias. You can also log in using social media logins.

You can delete your user account by sending us a request by filling in the Contact Us form from our website. In case you decide to delete your personal data, all your data, including all communication, will be deleted. Information posted by you into our discussion forum will remain visible, but any link to your person will be deleted. The unique username you selected during the signup process will become available to other users upon deletion.

In addition to the extent of processing described above, when you post a comment we will retain your IP address for one month. This is necessary to defend ourselves from possible liability claims that may arise from unlawful comments posted by you and reflects our legitimate interest with regard to the legal justification of this processing activity in Article 6 sec. 1 sent. 1 lit. f GDPR.

We reserve the right to delete comments that are off-topic, spam, abusive, use excessive foul language, include ad hominem attacks or offend against legal regulations. 

## V. Online advertising

This website uses online advertising services to present you with ads that meet your interests. Respective advertisement is labelled with the name of the provider, e.g. "Google-Ad". Additionally, this service helps us to improve our website and to make your visit more interesting. In order to do so, we collect statistical information about you that will be processed by the provider. This processing is based on Article 6 sec. 1 sent. 1 lit. f GDPR and represents our legitimate interest to improve your website experience and to promote our products and services.

## 1\. Cookies, Web-beacons

Providers will be automatically informed about your visit on our website. For such purpose, a web beacon is used to place a cookie on your computer.

Please note that we neither have the control of the extent of personal data that is collected by the respective plug-in provider nor do we know the processing's purpose or the period your personal data will be retained. Depending on the provider your personal data may be transferred to and processed in third countries, e.g. the United States. For further information about the potential risks of a cross border data transfer please refer to section XII.

It is possible that a provider discloses your personal data to its business partners, third parties or authorities.

You can prevent the installation of such a cookie  
(i) by a respective setting of your browser that blocks the installation of third party cookies,  
(ii) by deactivating the provider's interest-related advertising under the link mentioned in the provider details below,  
(iii) or generally blocking cookies under e.g. <http://www.google.com/settings/ads/plugin>.

Further information about the processing of your personal data in the provider's course of operation is provided by its privacy policy. Moreover, you will be provided with further information with regard to your rights and settings concerning privacy. You can access the provider's privacy policy by following the link in the provider details below.

## 2\. Criteo

We use the Criteo-Service to advertise on our site and third party websites to previous visitors of our site. Criteo-Service is operated by Criteo SA, Rue Blanche, 75009, Paris, France (<http://www.criteo.com/>).

The advertisements are displayed on the basis of information that is stored in cookies which Criteo places on your computer. The text files include information, on your visit of our website, in particular product views that is read-out in the course of subsequent visits of this or third party websites for specific product recommendations. The cookie includes a random alias. In case you visit our website within a certain period of time and view our products, Criteo is able to recognize you by means of the alias. However, the information cannot be attributed to you personally. We or Criteo will not merge this information with your personal data and will not disclose any of your personal data to any third party. You can prevent the storing and using of information in a cookie placed by Criteo by clicking on the following link <http://www.criteo.com/en/privacy-policy> and using the controller next to "Opt-Out" by switching it to "ON".

When you opt out, a new cookie (Opt-Out-Cookie) is placed in your web browser that tells Criteo to cease data collection from and ad delivery to your browser. You can opt in to Criteo's ads again at any time by switching the controller to "OFF". Please be aware that this configuration will be necessary for each of your browsers. In case all of your cookies in a browser are deleted, also the Opt-Out-Cookie of Criteo will be affected.

## 3\. Google Adwords

We use Google Adwords to advertise on our site and third party websites to previous visitors of our site. Google Adwords is provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google").

The advertisements are displayed on the basis of information that is stored in cookies which Google places on your computer. The text files include information, on your visit of our website, in particular product views that is read-out in the course of subsequent visits of this or third party websites for specific product recommendations. The cookie includes a random alias. In case you visit our website within a certain period of time and view our products, Google is able to recognize you by means of the alias. However, the information cannot be attributed to you personally. We or Google will not merge this information with your personal data and will not disclose any of your personal data to any third party. You can prevent the storing and using of information in a cookie placed by Google by clicking on the following link <http://www.google.de/ads/preferences> and configuring your preferences there.

For more information about Google privacy policies see <https://privacy.google.com/intl/en/#> and <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/?hl=en>.

## VI. Analysis

For statistical analyses we use web analytics services to collect information about the use of this site.

## 1\. General tracking information

The tools collect information such as:

  * Device and browser information (operating system information, mobile device identifier, mobile operating system information, etc.)
  * IP address
  * Page accessed, URL click stream (the chronological order of our internet sites you visited)
  * Geographical location
  * Time of visit
  * Referring site, application, or service

We use the information we get from the providers only to determine the most useful information you are looking for, and to improve and optimise this website. We do not combine the information collected through the use of the tools with personal data. 

Depending on the provider the information generated about your use of the website may be transferred to and processed in third countries, e.g. the United States. For further information about the potential risks of a cross border data transfer, please refer to section XII. The tools collect only the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit this site, rather than your name or any other identifying information. The provider will use this information in order to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activities and to provide other services relating to website and internet use to us.

The legal basis for this processing is Art. 6 sec. 1 sent. 1 lit. f GDPR and represents our legitimate interest to analyse our website's traffic to improve the user's experience and to optimise the website in general. We use Audience as an online profiling mechanism where data collected are fully anonymized. Audience is a log tracking system that compares real-time the behaviour of users against profiles, and helps trigger actions.

## 2\. Google Analytics / Google Tag Manager

We use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google"). On our behalf Google will use the information generated by a cookie for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity and providing other services relating to website activity and internet activity in connection with the use of the website. 

We have activated the IP-anonymisation within the Google Analytics service, and your IP address will be truncated within the area of member states of the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases the whole IP address will be first transferred to a Google server in the USA and truncated there. The IP-address your browser conveys within the scope of Google Analytics will not be associated with any other data held by Google.

You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser; however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. In addition to that you may prevent the collection of the information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including you IP address) and the processing of this data by Google if you download and install the browser plug-in available at the following link: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

## VII. Third party content and social media plug-ins

## 1\. Social media plug-ins

We use the following social media plug-ins: Facebook, Twitter, Tumblr, and Reddit. This allows you to communicate with such services and like or comment from our website. Social media plug-ins enable a direct communication between your device and the servers of the social media provider, allowing the social media provider to communicate with you and collect information about you browsing our website. This processing is based on Article 6 sec. 1 sent. 1 lit. f GDPR and represents our legitimate interest to improve your website experience and to optimise our services.

Your personal data may be transferred to and processed in countries where social media plug-ins are provided from. For further information about the potential risks of a cross border data transfer refer to IX.

Transfer of personal data takes places whether you have an account with the provider or not.

Please note that we neither have the control of the extent of personal data that is collected by the respective plug-in provider nor do we know the processing's purpose or the period your personal data will be retained.

Further information about the processing of your personal data in the provider's course of operation is provided via their respective privacy policy. Moreover, you will be provided with further information with regard to your rights and setting concerning privacy.

**a) Facebook Social Plugins**

We use so-called social plugins ("plugins") of the social networking site facebook.com provided by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA ("Facebook"). The plugins can be identified by one of Facebook's logos (white "f" on blue tile or a "thumps-up" sign) or by the additional text "Facebook Social Plugin". The list of Facebook Social Plugins and their appearance can be accessed via: <http://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins>.

If a user visits one of the websites using such a plugin, the user's browser directly connects to Facebook's servers. The plugin and its content are made available directly on Facebook's servers and included in the website by the user's browser. Due to the integration of the plugin Facebook collects the information that a user is visiting the corresponding website. If the user is logged in on Facebook at the moment he or she visits the website, Facebook may be able to connect the visit on the website to the user's Facebook account. If the user interacts with the plugin – for example if he or she presses the like button or comments on something – the user's browser transmits this information to Facebook. Facebook stores this information. If a user is not a member of Facebook, Facebook may collect and store the user's IP-address. Facebook states that it only collects anonymized IP-addresses in Germany.

The reason for and scope of the data acquisition and information about the way in which the data is processed and used by Facebook, as well as the user's rights in this respect and settings options for protecting the users privacy can be found under: <http://www.facebook.com/policy.php>.

If the user is a member of Facebook and does not wish Facebook to collect personal data via this homepage and to link this with his data stored on Facebook, the user needs to log off from Facebook before going to this homepage.

The user may also block Facebook's plugins using add-ons for the user's browser, for example the "Facebook Blocker".

**b) Twitter**

We use the Twitter button. The button is provided by Twitter Inc., 795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA. ("Twitter") The buttons are marked using the text "Twitter" or "Follow" and a stylized blue bird. The button enables the user to share an article or a website of this homepage on Twitter or to follow the provider on Twitter.

If a user visits one of the websites using such a button, the user's browser directly connects to Twitter's servers. The Twitter button and its content are loaded directly from Twitter's servers and included in the website by the user's browser. According to the provider's knowledge, Twitter collects the user IP-address and the website's URL when the button is loaded from Twitter's servers. However, this data is only be used for loading and displaying the Twitter button.

Further information can be found in Twitter's privacy statement under: <https://twitter.com/privacy>. Should you have any questions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us via the e-mail address [dataprotection@springer.com](mailto:dataprotection@springer.com).

**c) Tumblr**

We use Tumblr button. The button is provided by Tumblr, Inc. 35 E. 21st St., 9th Floor, New York, NY 10010 USA. The button is marked using the text 'Tumblr' and 't'.

The button enables the user to share an article or a website of this homepage on Tumblr or to follow the provider on Tumblr. 

If a user visits one of the websites using such a button, the user's browser directly connects to Tumblr's servers. The Tumblr button and its content are loaded directly from Tumblr's servers and included in the website by the user's browser. According to the provider's knowledge, Tumblr collects the user IP-address and the website's URL when the button is loaded from Tumblr's servers. However, this data is only be used for loading and displaying the Tumblr button.

Further information can be found in Tumblr's privacy statement under: <https://www.tumblr.com/privacy>.

Should you have any questions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us via the e-mail address [dataprotection@springer.com](mailto:dataprotection@springer.com).

**d) Reddit**

We use Reddit button. The button is provided by Reddit Inc. 520 3rd Street, San Francisco, CA 94107 USA. The button is marked using the text 'Reddit' and its alien logo 'Snoo'.

The button enables the user to share an article or a website of this homepage on Reddit or to follow the provider on Reddit.

If a user visits one of the websites using such a button, the user's browser directly connects to Reddit's servers. The Reddit button and its content are loaded directly from Reddit's servers and included in the website by the user's browser. According to the provider's knowledge, Reddit collects the user IP-address and the website's URL when the button is loaded from Reddit's servers. However, this data is only be used for loading and displaying the Reddit button.

Further information can be found in Reddit's privacy statement under: <https://www.redditinc.com/policies/privacy-policy>.

Should you have any questions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us via the e-mail address [dataprotection@springer.com](mailto:dataprotection@springer.com).

## 2\. External providers

We use the YouTube service in order to play videos directly from our website. The videos are created by Macmillan Education. We also use DPS (@IDM) to collect and store dictionary data for the Open Dictionary. This processing is based on Article 6 sec. 1 sent. 1 lit. f GDPR and represents our legitimate interest to improve your website experience and to optimise our services.

Your browser will directly communicate with YouTube LLC, 901 Cherry Ave., San Bruno, CA 94066, USA. We do not have any influence on YouTube and IDM, whose contact address is 27, rue Albert Einstein, 77421 Champs-sur-Marne, France, data processing activities. Please check YouTube and IDM's privacy policy for further information: <https://policies.google.com/privacy> and <http://www.idmgroup.com/legal/idm-privacy-cookie-notices.html>. Here you can find information about your rights and privacy settings. Your data may be sent to a country outside the EEA. For further information about the potential risks of a cross border data transfer refer to 5.

## 3\. Links to third party websites

This website may contain links to third party websites. We are not responsible for the content and the data collection on respective third party websites; please check the privacy policy of respective websites for information of respective websites' data processing activities.

## VIII. Information sharing

Your personal data will only be disclosed to a third party to the extent necessary to fulfill our contractual relationship. Legal basis for the transfer of your personal data is Article 6 sec. 1 sent. 1 lit. b and f GDPR and represents our legitimate interest to implement our general terms and conditions of business or any other agreements concluded with you.

We may disclose anonymous aggregate statistics about users of the website in order to describe our services to prospective partners, advertisers and other reputable third parties and for other lawful purposes, but these statistics will include no personal data. 

We may disclose your personal data to following contractors who assist us in providing the services we offer through the website

  * Ingenierie Diffusion Multimedia, 27, rue Albert Einstein, 77421 Champs-sur-Marne, France

Such a transfer will be based on data processing agreements. Therefore, our contractors will only use your personal data to the extent necessary to perform their functions and will be contractually bound to process your personal data only on our behalf and in compliance with our requests.

In the event that we undergo re-organisation or are sold to a third party, any personal data we hold about you may be transferred to that re-organised entity or third party in compliance with applicable law.

We may disclose your personal data if legally entitled or required to do so (for example if required by law or by a court order).

## IX. Cross border data transfers

Within the scope of our information sharing activities set out above, your personal data may be transferred to other countries (including countries outside the EEA) which may have different data protection standards from your country of residence. Please note that data processed in a foreign country may be subject to foreign laws and accessible to foreign governments, courts, law enforcement, and regulatory agencies. However, we will endeavour to take reasonable measures to maintain an adequate level of data protection when sharing your personal data with such countries.

In the case of a transfer to a country outside of the EEA, this transfer is safeguarded by _EU Standard Contractual Clauses_. You can find further information about the aforementioned safeguards under: <https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection_en>. You can find further information about the aforementioned safeguards by contacting the Group Data Protection Officer via [dataprotection@springer.com](mailto:dataprotection@springer.com).

## X. Security

We have reasonable state of the art security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of personal data under our control. For example, our security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary and only authorised personnel have access to personal data. Whilst we cannot ensure or guarantee that loss, misuse or alteration of information will never occur, we use all reasonable efforts to prevent it.

You should bear in mind that submission of information over the internet is never entirely secure. We cannot guarantee the security of information you submit via our website whilst it is in transit over the internet and any such submission is at your own risk.

## XI. Data retention

We strive to keep our processing activities with respect to your personal data as limited as possible. In the absence of specific retention periods set out in this policy, your personal data will be retained only for as long as we need it to fulfil the purpose for which we have collected it and, if applicable, as long as required by statutory retention requirements.

## XII. Your rights

Under the legislation applicable to you, you may be entitled to exercise some or all of the following rights:

1\. require (i) information as to whether your personal data is retained and (ii) access to and/or duplicates of your personal data retained, including the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned, and the data recipients as well as potential retention periods;  
2\. request rectification, removal or restriction of your personal data, e.g. because (i) it is incomplete or inaccurate, (ii) it is no longer needed for the purposes for which it was collected, or (iii) the consent on which the processing was based has been withdrawn;  
3\. refuse to provide and – without impact to data processing activities that have taken place before such withdrawal – withdraw your consent to processing of your personal data at any time;  
4\. object, on grounds relating to your particular situation, that your personal data shall be subject to a processing. In this case, please provide us with information about your particular situation. After the assessment of the facts presented by you we will either stop processing your personal data or present you our compelling legitimate grounds for an ongoing processing;  
5\. take legal actions in relation to any potential breach of your rights regarding the processing of your personal data, as well as to lodge complaints before the competent data protection regulators;  
6\. require (i) to receive the personal data concerning you, which you have provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and (ii) to transmit those data to another controller without hindrance from our side; where technically feasible you shall have the right to have the personal data transmitted directly from us to another controller; and/or  
7\. not to be subject to any automated decision making, including profiling (automatic decisions based on data processing by automatic means, for the purpose of assessing several personal aspects) which produce legal effects on you or affects you with similar significance.  

You may (i) exercise the rights referred to above or (ii) pose any questions or (iii) make any complaints regarding our data processing by contacting us using the contact details set out below.

## XIII. Contacting us

Please submit any questions, concerns or comments you have about this privacy policy or any requests concerning your personal data by email to our Group Data Protection Officer. You can contact our Group Data Protection Officer via [dataprotection@springer.com](mailto:dataprotection@springer.com).

The information you provide when contacting us <https://www.macmillandictionary.com/contact.html> will be processed to handle your request and will be erased when your request is completed. Alternatively, we will restrict the processing of the respective information in accordance with statutory retention requirements.
